LYNDSAY RICHES

Graphic Designer



416-555-7890

Oakville, ON

Bē behance.net/lynzriches

EDUCATION

GAME PROGRAMMING - 2022 - Present

Centennial College

WCAG 2.0/AODA TRAINING - 2017

Six Nations Elected Council

WEB DESIGN - 2017/18

McMaster University Centre for Continuing Education

SKILLS

- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Acrobat
- Microsoft Word/Excel/ PowerPoint
- HTML/CSS/Wordpress
- Constant Contact
- Layout & Typography
- Social Media Content Creation & Editing
- Design for Print/ Pre-press
- Logo Creation
- Illustration
- Branding
- Mock-ups/Sketches
- C# / Unity
- 2D Game Assets & UI Elements

PROFILE

Experienced graphic designer with a broad skill set obtained over 20+ years in the design industry that includes social media management, communications, web design, branding and print production, both in-house as part of a team and independently/remotely.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer

July 2018 - Present

ALLEGRA MARKETING PRINT MAIL - BURLINGTON, ON

- Design logos, signage, branding packages and other marketing materials for varied customer base, working from design briefs or meetings with clients
- Schedule and evaluate performance of social media content
- Ensure all projects adhere to any visual brand guidelines on a per-customer basis
- Organize and archive files for ease of retrieval for future use
- Prepare files for high quality print production via in-house production and/or external vendors

Communications Assistant

March 2017 - December 2018 (Contract)

SIX NATIONS ELECTED COUNCIL - OHSWEKEN, ON

- Create and edit communications and marketing pieces for outreach to media, corporations and the community
- Designed & illustrated a Recycling Handbook for distribution to the Six Nations Community to raise awareness of local recycling program
- Monitor social media and other press outlets to facilitate timely response to news events
- Refined supplied sketches to develop the new SNEC logo and brand standards
- Developed mockups and design concepts for new SNEC website
- Ensure designs meet accessibility (WCAG/AODA) standards

Graphic Designer/Pre-Press Operator

January - October 2016

THE PRINTING KORNER - WATERDOWN, ON

- Creative collaboration with clients to design engaging & effective advertising and marketing pieces, logos and other documents
- Prepare files for cost-efficient output to digital copiers, wide format print or for external production

Graphic Designer/Pre-Press Operator

March 2004 - April 2015

SPENCE PRINT SOLUTIONS - BRANTFORD, ON

- Engage with clients to design logos, flyers, postcards and other marketing materials
- Preflight and prepare supplied files for accurate and efficient print production (internally and with external vendors)